euractiv.com 2019-05-21

# EURACTIV Privacy Policy – EURACTIV.com

Effective date: May 23, 2018

EURACTIV.COM is a private limited company registered in the United Kingdom.

Address: 150 Aldersgate Street, London, EC1AB

VAT GB702888226

Email: [info@euractiv.com](mailto:info@euractiv.com)

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. (“us”, “we”, or “our”) operates the following websites with their newsletters (collectively called the “Service”):

[www.euractiv.com](http://www.euractiv.com/) and its subdomains, including  <http://jobs.euractiv.com/>, <http://pr.euractiv.com/>, <http://agenda.euractiv.com/>, [www.events.euractiv.com](http://www.events.euractiv.com/)

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible at https://www.euractiv.com/terms-conditions/

## **Definitions**

### **Personal Data**

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

### **Usage Data**

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

### **Cookies**

Cookies are small pieces of data stored on a User’s device.

### **Data Controller**

Data Controller means a person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal data are, or are to be, processed.

For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your data.

### **Data Processor (or Service Providers)**

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any person (other than an employee of the Data Controller) who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller.

We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

### **Data Subject**

Data Subject is any living individual who is the subject of Personal Data.

### **User**

The User is the individual using our Service. The User corresponds to the Data Subject, who is the subject of Personal Data.

## **Data Collection and Use**

We collect several different types of data for various purposes to provide and improve our Service to you.

### **Types of Data Collected**

#### **_Personal Data_**

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you (“Personal Data”). Personally, identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

  * Contact data (Email address, telephone number)
  * First name and last name
  * Geographic data (Address, Country, City, ZIP/Postal code etc)
  * Organisation and position
  * Demographic data
  * Online identifiers (username, IP etc)

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

#### **_Usage Data_**

We may also collect information on how the Service is accessed and used (“Usage Data”). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer’s Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### **_Tracking Cookies Data_**

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service.

Examples of Cookies we use:

  * **Session Cookies.** We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
  * **Preference Cookies.** We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
  * **Security Cookies.** We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
  * **Advertising Cookies.** Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

Most of the data we collect is collected directly from the data subject. We collect some data from 3rd party sources via cookies. For more details about cookies consult our [cookie policy](https://www.euractiv.com/about-euractiv/euractiv-com-cookie-policy/).

## **Use of Data**

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. uses the collected data for various purposes:

  * To provide and maintain our Service
  * To notify you about changes to our Service
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
  * To provide you with our newsletters
  * To serve relevant advertising
  * To provide customer support
  * To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
  * To monitor the usage of our Service
  * To detect, prevent and address technical issues
  * To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

## Legal basis for data processing

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. uses several legal bases for processing data:

  * consent
  * performance of a contract
  * compliance with legal obligations
  * legitimate interest of EURACTIV.COM Ltd., such as for marketing purposes, to control the regular operation of the Service, to defend our rights or to improve our website.

## **Retention of Data**

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies.

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

## **Transfer of Data**

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

The data that we collect is mostly processed in Belgium.

EURACTIV transfers data to a country outside the European Economic Area only when that country ensures an adequate level of protection within the meaning of the legislation in force and, in particular, within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (for more information on the countries offering an adequate level of protection, see: <https://goo.gl/1eWt1V>), or within the limits permitted by the legislation in force, for example by ensuring the protection of data by appropriate contractual provisions.

If you wish, you can obtain a copy of the adapted contractual clauses by sending an email to privacy@euractiv.com

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

## **Disclosure of Data**

### **Business Transaction**

If EURACTIV.COM Ltd. is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

### **Disclosure for Law Enforcement**

Under certain circumstances, EURACTIV.COM Ltd. may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### **Legal Requirements**

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

  * To comply with a legal obligation
  * To protect and defend the rights or property of EURACTIV.COM Ltd.
  * To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
  * To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
  * To protect against legal liability

## **Security of Data**

The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

## **Your Rights**

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data.

Whenever made possible, you can update your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to change your Personal Data, please contact us to make the required changes.

If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us by filling in the form on our [contact page](https://www.euractiv.com/contactus/).

You have the right:

  * To access and receive a copy of the Personal Data we hold about you
  * To rectify any Personal Data held about you that is inaccurate
  * To request the deletion of Personal Data held about you
  * To withdraw your consent over the processing of your data
  * You have the right to data portability for the information you provide to EURACTIV.COM Ltd.. You can request to obtain a copy of your Personal Data in a commonly used electronic format so that you can manage and move it.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests.

You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK supervisory authority [ICO](https://ico.org.uk/) or your national supervisory authority.

## **Service Providers**

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service (“Service Providers”), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analysing how our Service is used.

These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

**Technical services**

We may use third-party services to help you log in more easily on the website or to extend the functionality of our Service.

**Google Tag Manager**

Google Tag Manager is a service offered by Google that allows us to deploy other services on the website. Google Tag Manager does not collect any of your personal data.

**Logging into our Service**

You may use your Google, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn and Microsoft to log in easier on our website. Our Service receives an identification token from these platforms to make the login process easier. Our Service does not store your personal information from any of these platforms.

### **Analytics**

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

**Google Analytics**

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

**New Relic**

New Relic is a technical monitoring service offered by the company with the same name. This service is collecting usage data on the technical performance of our service. You can read their privacy policy here: <https://newrelic.com/termsandconditions/privacy>

**Content Insights**

Content Insights is an analytics service offered by Content Insights EAD that tracks and reports website traffic. Content Insights EAD monitors your use of the Service. It processes the data in accordance with their Privacy Policy: https://contentinsights.com/privacypolicy

**Newsletters**

**MailChimp**

We use MailChimp as our newsletter sending platform. By using our Service, you acknowledge that some of the information you provide will be transferred to MailChimp for processing in accordance with their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms of Use](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/).

### **Advertising**

We may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you to help support and maintain our Service.

**Google AdSense DoubleClick Cookie**

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet.

You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: <http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/>

### **Behavioral Remarketing**

EURACTIV.COM Ltd. uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

**Google AdWords**

Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc.

You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: <http://www.google.com/settings/ads>

Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on – <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> – for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy Terms web page: <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>

**Twitter**

Twitter remarketing service is provided by Twitter Inc.

You can opt-out from Twitter’s interest-based ads by following their instructions: <https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170405>

You can learn more about the privacy practices and policies of Twitter by visiting their Privacy Policy page: <https://twitter.com/privacy>

**Facebook**

Facebook remarketing service is provided by Facebook Inc.

You can learn more about interest-based advertising from Facebook by visiting this page: <https://www.facebook.com/help/164968693837950>

To opt-out from Facebook’s interest-based ads follow these instructions from Facebook: <https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217>

Facebook adheres to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising established by the Digital Advertising Alliance. You can also opt-out from Facebook and other participating companies through the Digital Advertising Alliance in the USA <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, the Digital Advertising Alliance of Canada in Canada <http://youradchoices.ca/> or the European Interactive Digital Advertising Alliance in Europe <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>, or opt-out using your mobile device settings.

For more information on the privacy practices of Facebook, please visit Facebook’s Data Policy: <https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation>

**LinkedIn**

LinkedIn remarketing service is offered as part of the LinkedIn Marketing Solutions pack. To read more about how LinkedIn Marketing solutions comply with GDPR read this FAQ: <https://www.linkedin.com/help/linkedin/answer/87080/linkedin-marketing-solutions-and-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr-?lang=en>  
For LinkedIn’s Privacy Policy go here: <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>

## **Obligation to provide data**

As a website user, you are under no statutory or contractual obligation to provide your personal data to us. If you enter into a contractual relationship with us, you may need to provide some personal data for the purpose of the realisation of the contract.

## **Links to Other Sites**

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit.

We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services.

## **Children’s Privacy**

Our Service does not address anyone under the age of 18 (“Children”).

We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 18. If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without verification of parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

## **Changes to This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page.

We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the “effective date” at the top of this Privacy Policy.

You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## Jurisdiction

The current Privacy Policy is subject to Belgian law. For cases related to the current document, we appoint the court in Brussels, Belgium as the competent one.

## **Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us:

  * By email: privacy@euractiv.com
  * By visiting this page on our website: <http://www.euractiv.com/privacy>
